

Goal Oriented product developer with 7+ years of experience, seeking roles in Web Development. Proficient in ASP.NET C#, MVC, .NET Core, Restful API, LINQ, SQL Server, Entity Framework, Microsoft Azure and Design patterns



Current Designation: Software Developer Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: SIEMENS Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E.
Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: ASP.Net MVC,Entity Framework,C#,LINQ,WCF,TDD,SQL Server Development,Web

API, JQuery, HTML, CSS, JSON, . Net Core, mog, Microsoft Azure, NUnit

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Ambitious and goal oriented product developer with excellent communication skills having 7+ years of experience in Asp.Net C#, MVC, Web API, LINQ, Entity Framework, SQL Server, JQuery, Microsoft Azure and software design patterns like Singleton, Facade, Repository (Dependency Injection). I am looking forward to acquiring more knowledge as new technologies comes in and apply the same in my career and grow along with the organization that will purposefully utilize my qualifications

Work Experience

SIEMENS as Software Developer

Feb 2019 to Till Date

As technical lead, I am involved in all phases of the application development from requirements analysis, design, development, and testing of the application.

Converting business requirement into code.

- -> Writing of code for complex business logics
- -> Leading and mentoring the team of 7
- -> Working with various teams and stakeholders to get inputs needed
- -> Working as per Agile methodology

HEWLETT PACKARD ENTERPRISE PRIVATE LIMITED as Software Developer

Apr 2017 to Feb 2019

As a developer I was responsible for many phases of s/w development lifecycle including technical research, requirement analysis and creating high level design

- -> Writing and debugging code for new Implementation
- -> Written and modified existing stored procedures to handle business functionality
- -> Resolved bugs reported by testing team

Infosys as Senior Systems Engineer

Aug 2013 to Mar 2017

As a developer I was responsible for many phases of s/w development lifecycle including technical research, requirement analysis and creating high level design

- -> Writing and debugging code for new Implementation
- -> Written and modified existing stored procedures to handle business functionality
- -> Resolved bugs reported by testing team
- -> Writing of code for complex business logics

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Engineering College, Kota in 2012

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Microsoft SQL server

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
.Net Core		2020	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
SQL Server		2020	7 Year(s) 4 Month(s)	
VISUAL STUDIO		2020	7 Year(s) 4 Month(s)	
C#		2020	7 Year(s) 4 Month(s)	
Entity Framework		2020	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
RESTful API		2020	4 Year(s) 6 Month(s)	
ASP.Net MVC		2020	5 Year(s) 6 Month(s)	
Microsoft Azure		2020	0 Year(s) 6 Month(s)	
NUNIT		2020	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: TIA - Totally Integrated Automation

Client: Automation Industry
Nature of Employment: Full Time
Project Location: Bangalore
Role: Programmer
Duration: Feb 2019 - Oct 2020
Onsite / Offsite: Offsite
Team Size: 10

Skill Used: C#.Net, .NET Core, Design Patterns, XAML

Project Details: TIA is an automation tool used in leading Automobile industries across the world.

It is used in the manufacturing industries to monitor and track the power consumption and electricity leakage in the circuit. With the help of TIA, the operators can optimize the power consumption from the machineries or electrical equipment by analyzing their operations at various conditions. With the single tool its possible to configure, parametrize and program our devices along with the Automation devices such as PLCs, HMI panels, Drives, etc.

Project Title: Medicaid Information Management system

Client: Kansas state

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Apr 2017 - Dec 2018
Project Location: Bengaluru Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer

Team Size: 10

Skill Used: Asp.net C#, MVC, Web API, WCF, SQL, LINQ, Entity Framework, Visual studio 2017, SQL Server management

studio

Project Details: Medicaid Information Management System is a website to manage claims processing and information retrieval that State Medicaid programs must have to be eligible for Federal funding. It takes care of the automated claims processing and subsystems that support program integrity activities, such as provider screening, claims processing, and utilization reviews.

Project Title: UK Marketing Company

Client: AstraZeneca

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2015 - Jul 2016 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Project Location: Chennai

Role: Programmer Team Size: 1

Skill Used: ASP.Net, ASP.Net Ajax, Javascript, SQL Server, IIS Server

Role Description: Responsible for enhancement and development for all the applications individually at all levels.

Project Details: UK Marketing Company consists of a set of 15 applications.

Project Title: Microbiological Systems Reporting

Client: Astra Zeneca

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jul 2014 - Dec 2014 Project Location: Chennai Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 5

Skill Used: ASP.NET 4.5, SQL SERVER 2012, AJAX, Javascript

Role Description: Module leader and also was responsible for designing and developing the website. Also involved in unit

testing and regression testing.

Project Details: MRS is a Web Application used by AstraZeneca Labs throughout the UK to manage and report on environmental room monitoring. The software was developed by closely working with quality assurance professionals to make sure that we meet their requirements, the latest MHRA standards and Good Manufacturing Practice. The application was used for preparing and testing samples of medicines and generated reports which was ultimately used by the doctors.

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time